蓝光电影网
blu-raydisc.tv
末日崩塌
圣费尔南多谷
?...你的眼神里?
...look in your eye
?而我有着红唇和那些优雅 都是你所爱的?
And I got that red lip classic thing that you like
?每当我们横冲直撞 却总能和好如初?
And when we go crashing down, we come back every time
?因为我们永远如经典般存在?
'Cause we never go out of style
?我们永不过时?
We never go out of style
?你留着长发 梳着大背头 穿着白色T恤?
You got that long hair, slicked back, white t-shirt
?而我有着好女孩的样子 穿着紧身裙?
And I got that good girl faith and a tight little skirt
?每当我们横冲直撞 却总能和好如初?
And when we go crashing down, we come back every time
?因为我们永远如经典般存在?
'Cause we never go out of style
?我们永不过时?
We never go out of style
啊
Aah!
救命
Help!
我知道你们都隶属于驻扎在阿富汗巴格拉姆
So, uh, I understand that you all were part
军事基地的五十八号救援分队
of the fifty-eighth rescue squadron staged over at bagram
执行空中巡逻营救任务
in Afghanistan for combat search and rescue.
是的 女士 去过两次
Yes, ma'am. Two tours.
你们现在仍然是搭档吗
And you're still flying together?
是的 我们感情都挺好的 像一家人一样
Yeah, we all got pretty tight over there. Wouldn't break up the family.
兄弟 我们像是一家的吗
Dude, do we look like family?
一点点吧
A little.
那么 在阿富汗时的救援
So, what's the biggest difference
和在这里的工作有什么不同吗
between rescuing over there and what you do here?
这里不会吃枪子儿
Not getting shot at.
你真是个有趣的家伙
You're a funny guy.
可爱、机灵
是吧 一般般啦
Yeah. Not exactly.
呃 盖恩斯首长
Um... chief Gaines?
据我所知在阿富汗和洛杉矶消防局任期间
I'm told that between Afghanistan and LAFD,
你拯救了超过六百余人的生命
you have over six hundred documented rescues.
这真让人印象深刻
That's, uh...pretty impressive.
本职工作而已 女士
Just doin' my job, ma'am.
绝对服从命令
Go where they tell me to go.
很不错 你可以停止拍摄了
That's great. You can cut there.
她在那里
There she is.
峡谷太窄了
Looks pretty tight.
把她拉上来
Take her up.
风向不断在变化
Winds are variable.
在270度到300度间摇摆
Two-seven-zero to three-zero-zero.
风速由十节上升为十五节
Ten knots gusting to fifteen.
呼叫总部 洛杉矶消防队
Metro, this is LAFD.
五号直升机已到达事故现场
Helo five on scene of cliff-v rescue.
我们看到了受困者
We have visual.
- 收到 直升机五号 - 那女孩叫什么
- Copy, Helo five. - What's the girl's name?
纳塔莉
Natalie.
总部 把她的手机转到我们这
Metro, connect her cell to our sat phone.
直升机五号 你们已经连上了
Helo five, you're connected.
你好
Hello?
纳塔莉 我是机长雷蒙德盖恩斯
Natalie, this is chief pilot Raymond Gaines
来自洛杉矶消防局
of the Los Angeles fire department.
我正开着直升机在你上方
I'm piloting the chopper above you.
你还好吗
You holdin' up all right?
我不知道 感觉不太好
I don't know. I'm not feeling very well.
天哪 车子正在下滑
Oh, my God! The car is sliding.
纳塔莉 我需要你保持冷静 亲爱的
Natalie, I'm gonna need you to stay calm, honey.
- 我们现在来救你 好吗 - 好吧
- We're coming to get you, okay? - Okay.
有七英里的能见度
Seven miles visibility.
风向270 风速10节
19 winds are at two seven zero at ten knots.
你只有一小时十五分钟的时间
We show you one plus one five playtime.
兄弟 我可没看到能从哪进去
Man, I don't see a way in.
我们得横向切入
We're gonna tip the hat.
横向切入吗
Tip the hat?
是啊 你最好抓紧了
Yeah. You might wanna hold on to somethin'.
出发
Here we go.
还能下降十五英尺
Fifteen feet out.
十英尺
Ten feet.
五英尺
Five.
哇 慢点 雷
Whoa, Whoa, easy, Ray.
好了 差不多了
All right. You got it.
好了 开工了 伙计们
All right. Tuck 'em in, boys.
乔比 别用吊篮
Joby, forget the basket.
我们这次得用上双重固定
We gotta do a double tie-in on this one.
车子要是掉下去了 她也就完了
That car goes, so does she.
门开了
Door's open.
拿上这个
Get this.
绳索固定
Hookin' up.
已经就位了
On the skid.
我们最多只有五分钟
We got five minutes max.
超过五分钟会怎样
What happens in five minutes?
没什么 只不过引擎会熄火
It's no big deal. Just engine failure.
好在我只要三分钟
Good thing I only need three.
- 谢天谢地 - 不 不 纳塔莉 别...
- Oh, thank God. - No, no! Natalie, do not...
天哪 天哪 把我救出去
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! Get me out of here.
纳塔莉 我需要你一动不动地待着
Natalie, I need you to stay perfectly still.
- 我要先稳定住汽车 好吗 - 快点 求你了
- I have to stabilize the car, okay? - Hurry, please.
车子固定好了
Car secured.
挂住了
Got it.
怎么回事
What the hell?
该死
Shit.
哇 哇
Whoa, Whoa!
迪伦 天哪 你没事吧
Dylan! Oh, my God. Are you all right?
天哪 乔比被卡住了
Jesus. Joby's pinned!
啊 该死的
Ah, goddamn it.
乔比 我现在下来
Joby, I'm comin' down.
哈里森 你来驾驶 马库斯 给我装上安全绳
Harrison, you're flyin'. Marcus, rig me a rope.
- 移交驾驶权 - 收到
- Handin' over. - Roger.
已接手
Takin' over.
- 随时切断绳子 - 收到
- Be ready to cut. - Roger that.
钩上了
Hooked up.
出舱门
Out the door.
我准备好了
Ray's clear.
纳塔莉 别担心 我会把你救出...
Natalie, don't you worry. I'm gonna get you outta...
啊
Aaah!
直升机撑不住了
This thing isn't gonna hold!
雷 红色警报 我们要坠机了
Ray, we are in the red! We are going to crash!
纳塔莉 我们现在就出去
Natalie, we are going now!
我抓住你了
I got you.
切绳子 乔比 快甩开
Cut it! Joby, swing!
太好了
Yeah!
我们现在送你回家怎么样
What do we say we get you home now.
我觉得这主意实在不错
I think that's a really good idea.
发生在日本的仙台地震被认为是
Now the sendai quake in Japan was considered to be
1900年以来最强的五大地震之一
one of the five strongest since 1900.
威力巨大 事实上
It was so powerful, in fact,
它将日本的本土移动了八英尺
that it moved the main island of Japan eight feet.
这仅仅是每年发生在全球范围内
This is just one of the 1.3 million earthquakes
130万起地震中的一次而已
that occur around the globe each year.
北美最大的一次地震发生于1964年
The largest ever recorded here in North America:
在阿拉斯加州的安克雷奇 有9.1级
Anchorage, Alaska, 1964. A 9.1.
地震持续了有五分钟
The earth shook for five straight minutes.
释放出的能量
The energy release
相当于一千万等量的原子弹
was the equivalent of ten million atom bombs
等同于在日本广岛投下的原子弹
the size of the one dropped on Hiroshima.
但那不是史上记载最强的一次地震
And that's not the biggest earthquake ever recorded.
最强的一次是在四年前
No, the biggest was four years earlier
发生在智利南部的瓦尔迪维亚
off the coast of Valdivia in Southern Chile.
达到了9.5里氏震级
A 9.5 on the Richter scale.
就是那
Right there.
砰
Bam.
这次地震持续了十一分钟
This quake lasted eleven minutes and spawned a Tsunami
引起了82英尺的海啸 并将八千英里外的
eighty-two feet high that leveled hilo, Hawaii,
夏威夷西部夷为平地
eight thousand Miles away.
那可是八千英里之外啊
Eight thousand Miles away.
所以 嗯 正是因为地震有着
So, um, It's... It's mass destruction like this
如此之大的破坏性
that shows just how important
才显示出我们的研究和工作有多重要
the research that we're doing here is,
因为我们要能够预测地震
because we need to be able to predict these things.
对吗 可以提前应对
Right? To plan and prepare for them.
- 这位女士 - 教授 您认为
- Yes, ma'am. - Professor, do you think
那样的事情会发生在这里吗
something that intense could happen here?
额 圣安第斯断层
Well, the San Andreas fault
经过加利福尼亚附近
runs right up the spine of California.
两个构造板块的分界线
It's the demarcation line
近些年不断的在移动着
between two tectonic plates that are constantly moving.
再加上大约150年才会发生一次
Well, and add to that the fact that It's supposed to happen
较为严重的地震
every one hundred and fifty years
而我们已经安稳一百多年
and we're about a hundred years overdue.
我想说 这不是会不会发生的问题
I'd say It's not a matter of If.
而是何时会发生
It's a matter of when.
该死的 哥斯拉
Damn, Godzilla.
这次你们又对直升机做了什么
What the hell did you do to her this time?
和轿车玩了个小小的拔河比赛而已
Played a little tug of war with a car.
你要多久能把它修好
How soon before you get her fixed?
我今天会给马丁内斯打电话的
I'll call Martinez today.
干脆给你换件新的算了
Get a new one sent over to maintenance.
埃尔金 别走太快 小心你的屁股
Elgin, you move any faster, you're gonna break that hip.
洛杉矶消防局
哈里森说你要和布雷克一起休息几天
Harrison said you're taking off with Blake for a few days.
对 明天就走
Yeah. Leavin' tomorrow.
开车送她回去上学
Driving her back up to school.
周末排球队第一场比赛就开始了
Volleyball team has their first game this weekend,
洛杉矶消防局
驻扎地412
所以我想我们可以在海岸上玩一圈 露个营
so I figured we'd cruise up the coast. Do a little campin'.
伙计 我真不敢相信她已经上大学了
Dude, I can't believe she's in college already.
加州理工学院
地震学实验室 F
劳伦斯・海耶斯
基姆・帕克
我懂 时光飞逝 兄弟
I know. Too fast, brother.
- 我等会来找你 - 好的 伙计
- I'll catch you inside. - All right, man.
劳伦斯 你快看看这个
Lawrence, I gotta show you something.
什么 啊 小事情
Yeah? Aha. Easy. Easy.
我们刚刚发现了一个罕见的低级地震群
Now, we got a rare low-level seismic swarm
在内华达州的法尔科
out in Falco, Nevada.
24小时之内发生了23次小地震
Twenty-three small quakes, all tiny.
都很小 震级在2.0级到2.6级
2.0 to 2.6 in the last twenty-four hours.
好吧 内华达州的法尔科在哪啊
Okay. Where the hell is Falco, Nevada?
维加斯东南大约35英里
Thirty-five Miles southeast of Vegas,
或许离胡佛水坝五英里
maybe five Miles from the hoover dam.
好吧
Right.
那里没有断层啊
There aren't any faults out there.
不包括未知的啊
Any known faults.
如果我们现在过去 而那些迷你的地震还在持续的话
Now, If we get there while the mini quakes continue,
就可以测试我们的理论了
we can test our theory.
如果在地震前磁脉冲率上升的话
And If the magnetic pulse rate goes up before the quakes...
那么我们可以提前预测
Then we're predicting them.
我们可以提前预测
Then we are predicting them.
好了 让我们一探究竟吧
All right. Let's go check it out.
- 嗨 爸爸 - 嘿 亲爱的
- Hi, dad. - Hey, sweetie.
我在想还有没有地方放我的自行车
I was wondering If there was room for my bike.
我想我可以骑自行车去上课
I thought that I could ride it to class
这样我就不用花钱买停车证了
and then I wouldn't have to buy a parking pass.
好主意啊
That's a great idea.
我敢肯定我可以找到方法搞定的
I'm sure I could figure out a way to fit it in.
好的 很好
All right, great.
嗯 我在妈妈这里找不到钥匙
Um, I can't find the key to the lock at mom's,
可能是我落在化妆台左上角的抽屉里了
so It's either in the top left drawer of my dresser
也可能在我衣柜上面的粉红鞋盒里
or on top of the wardrobe in my pink shoe box.
好的 没问题 我会找到的
Okay, no problem. I'll find it.
今天有计划了吗
Don't know If you have plans tonight,
我想带你去吃晚餐
but I would love to take you to dinner.
你也可以把妈妈带着一起
You could even invite your mom along.
- 会很有趣的 - 噢 谢了 老爸
- Could be fun. - Oh, thanks, dad.
但我们已经计划和丹尼尔一起
But we already have plans with Daniel.
爸爸
Dad?
- 你还好吗 - 当然 我没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah, of course I am.
我好着呢 没问题
Totally cool. No problem at all.
好的 那我们明天见吧
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow, then.
好的
Okay.
噢 别忘了我的自行车钥匙
Oh, and don't forget the bike key.
不会忘的 放心
I won't. I got it.
再见 爸爸 爱你
Bye, dad. I love you.
我也爱你 宝贝
Okay. I love you, too, honey.
再见
Bye.
快过来 小家伙们 我们照张相
Come here, you guys. Let's take a picture.
劳伦斯 真是不可思议
Lawrence, It's incredible.
这是自我们来这之后第三次迷你地震了
This is the third mini quake since we've been here.
磁脉冲率上升的速度
And the magnetic pulse rate has increased
比之前都快
before each one of them.
我们找到规律了 朋友
We got a pattern, my friend.
是2.0级 我们真的预测到了
That was a 2.0. Our model's predictive.
哦 我们做到了 朋友 终于做到了
Oh! We got it right, man! Finally!
没错 我们成功了
Yep, we sure did.
噢 该死的
Oh, shit.
怎么了
What's wrong?
脉冲率又一次飙升了 这次很强烈
Pulse rates are spikin' again. They're huge.
你开玩笑吗
Are you serious?
基姆
Kim?
我们要遇到大地震了
We're about to have a major quake.
震级跳到7.1级了
It jumped to a 7.1!
我的天 基姆
Jesus, Kim!
快点离开那儿
Get the hell outta there!
所有人都快从大坝下去 快走 快
Everybody get off the dam! Move! Now! Now!
所有人都快点走 快点
Everybody off! Hurry up!
快到安全障碍后面来
Stay behind the barriers!
快点 快点 到安全障碍后面来
Come on! Come on! Come on! Stay behind the barriers!
基姆 快啊
Kim! Hurry!
快过来 我带你走
Come here. I got ya.
噢 我的天 快点 我的天
Oh, my God! Please! Oh, my God!
基姆 快跑啊
Kim! Hurry up!
劳伦斯
Lawrence!
基姆
Kim!
别 别动
No! No!
把眼睛闭起来吧
Close your eyes.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
内华达州南部今天发生强烈地震
The Southern part of Nevada was rocked today
地震专家称之为
by what seismologists are calling
本地区发生过的最为强烈的一次地震
the most destructive earthquake ever reported in that area.
官方报道称胡佛水坝已被完全摧毁
Officials are saying that hoover dam is a total loss.
哈瓦苏湖城 尼德尔斯 布莱斯和劳克林
Lake Havasu city, needles, blythe and Laughlin
也遭受了重大损失
also suffered major damage.
来自洛杉矶的救援
Additional support from Los Angeles
包括洛杉矶消防队的空中救援
including LAFD air rescue,
将会在24小时内抵达现场
is expected to begin arriving in the next 24 hours.
- 报道称 损失总量为 - 嗨 爸爸
- Reports that the total loss... - Hi, dad.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, honey.
我们刚刚看到新闻了
We just saw the news.
我知道 我很抱歉
I know. I'm so sorry.
我们明天就要出发了
We're headin' out tomorrow.
没关系 我知道的 这次太严重了 爸爸
No, I get it. This one's really bad, dad.
是啊 太可怕了
Yeah, this one's tough.
在地震期间 地震的强度
Earthquakes can rise and fall in intensity
会随着持续时间而有所增减
during their duration depending on the way...
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- Good to see you. - You, too.
你好 丹尼尔
Ah, Daniel.
- 雷 很开心终于见着你了 - 我也是
- Ray，good to finally meet you. - It's good to meet you, too.
这房子真不错啊
Heck of a place you got here, man.
- 啊 谢谢 - 不客气
- Ah, thank you. - Welcome.
那么 嗯 爸爸明天就要出发去内华达州了
So, um... dad is heading to Nevada tomorrow.
发生这样的事情真是可怕
Oh, It's terrible what happened.
在那儿要注意安全 好吗
Please be safe over there, okay?
好的 我们会的 还有 宝贝 我保证我会补偿你的
Yeah, we will. And I promise I'm gonna make it up to you, honey.
爸爸 真的没关系的
Dad, It's really no problem.
我开车没那么糟的
The drive is not that bad.
等等 为什么不让我带你过去呢
Wait. Why don't I take you up there.
我要飞旧金山参加个会仪
I'm flying up to San Francisco for a meeting.
然后我们可以一起去西雅图
We can head up to Seattle right after.
还能给我个看你那排球赛的机会
It'll give me an opportunity to catch a volleyball game.
好主意
That's a good idea.
还可以让你妈妈整理她的东西
And it'll give your mom a chance
省的我在碍手碍脚的
to get all her stuff moved in without me in the way.
好吧
Right.
你们要搬进来了吗
You guys movin' in?
是啊 我 我是想过要告诉你
Yeah. I-I was meaning to tell you,
但我们都没有机会
but we haven't had a chance to...
祝喜你们了
Congratulations.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
太好了
That's great.
整片社区都被冲毁了
Entire communities washed away.
到那儿以后打给我
Call me when you get there.
- 我会的 - 好的
- I will. - All right.
爸爸 我爱你 你一定要小心
I love you, dad. You be careful, please.
我会的 我会的 我也爱你
I will, I will. I love you, too.
当地政府提醒 可能还会
Local authorities caution that there could still be...
我去给她拿自行车
I'll get her bike.
很抱歉你们不能一起走
I'm sorry you guys can't go up there together.
我也感觉很糟糕
Yep. Me, too.
雷 雷
Ray. Ray.
我是想告诉你的
I was gonna tell you.
我们也是刚刚做的决定
We just decided to do it.
别多想了
Don't worry about it.
嘿 如果你想
Hey, If you want them...
我也会签好离婚协议给你的
I'll get those papers signed for you, too.
当时是周日下午
Um, it was a Sunday afternoon.
大家很显然都没有上班
Um, obviously, people weren't at work.
也没有睡觉
They weren't as... asleep.
即便如此 我们知道这次的破坏程度相当
Even so, we know the devastation was fairly...
太糟了
This is bad.
是啊
Yeah.
我们什么时候出发
What time we headin' out?
下午两点半 弟兄们都在准备救援装备
Fourteen-thirty. Guys are preppin' the gear now.
好了 开始工作吧
All right. Let's get to work.
这次的救援行动困难重重
It's a fairly sophisticated rescue operation underway.
这个叫丹尼尔的送布雷克过去
So this Daniel guy's taking Blake now?
我要是你的话就请病假了
I woulda just called in sick.
所以说我是头儿 你不是
Uh, It's why I'm the boss and you're not.
就算没有你的话 我们自己也能撑几天的
Oh, pretty sure we can manage a few days without ya.
鞋带松了
Shoe's untied.
哈哈哈
Ha-ha-ha-ha.
你在逗我吗
Are you kidding me?!
布雷克
Blake.
我想让你知道
I want you to know that I respect
我尊重你和你爸爸的感情
what you and your dad have.
我也知道你一下子很难
And I know that your mom moving in
接受我和你妈妈住在一起
has to feel like a pretty big step.
但我从未想过破坏你和你父亲的关系
But I'm never gonna try to change
或者取代他的位置
what you have with him or take his place.
好吗
Okay?
好的
Yeah.
很好 当然
Okay, cool.
嘿  你为什么一直没有孩子呢
Hey, how come you never had kids?
我有啊
Oh, I did.
这是其中一个
This is one of them right here.
她是旧金山空中一道
She's a pretty nice addition
- 亮丽的风景线 你不觉得吗 - 天门
- to the San Francisco skyline, don't you think? - "The gate."
- 很顺口 对吧 - 是啊 我很喜欢
- Catchy, right? Yeah, I like it.
妈妈跟我说过
Mom was telling me about this.
她说这是城中最高的建筑物 对吗
She said It's the tallest building in the city, right?
完工后不仅是最高的
When It's finished, it'll be the tallest,
也是最结实的 而且已经卖出了百分之八十
strongest and It's already eighty percent sold.
但说实话 我一直忙着盖楼
But, honestly, I guess I never had any kids
这也许就是我一直没有孩子的原因
'cause I was always so busy raising these.
妈妈发短信来了 她说她今天要和你妹妹一起吃午饭
Mom texted. She's having lunch with your sister today.
是啊 她只在城里呆几天
Yeah, she's only in town for a few days
真的很想见你妈妈
and really wanted to meet her.
不过我有点紧张
I'm a little nervous though.
苏珊对我保护欲有点过强了
Susan can be kind of overprotective.
谢谢
Thank you.
乔纳森
Jonathan.
早上好 里迪克先生
Good morning, Mr. Riddick.
早上好 你一个人能行吗 布雷克
Morning. Gonna be okay, Blake?
行的 我没事
Yeah, I'll be fine.
你好
Hi.
Hello.
我很抱歉 劳伦斯 我能帮什么忙吗
I'm sorry, Lawrence. Can I get you anything?
不用 我没事 阿列克谢 谢谢你
No. I'm fine, Alexi. Thank you.
你确定你想留在这里吗
Are you sure you want to be here?
这样可以转移我的注意力
I can use the distraction, actually.
什么事
Yeah?
外面来了个记者
There's a reporter outside.
她说自己在做一个关于内华达地震的报道
Says she's doing a segment on what happened in Nevada.
哦
Oh.
那我现在就去告诉她 改天再说
I'm gonna tell her that It's not a good time.
不 等等
No, wait a minute.
基姆为此付出了生命
Kim gave his life for this.
人们需要知道
People need to know
我们现在可以预测这些事
that we can predict these things now.
想要一本吗
You want a copy?
我有差不多一千本库存
I got about a thousand in storage.
地震之前 大概没有人会相信我们的话
No one listens to us until the ground shakes, I guess.
他们把你同事的遭遇告诉我了
You know, they told me what happened to your colleague.
我们不必现在就进行采访
We don't have to do this now.
不 就现在
Yeah, we do.
我们准备好了
We're good to go.
- 好的 - 好的
- Okay. - 'Kay.
开始
Rolling.
第一个问题 为什么
First question. How come
没有人预测出内华达州的灾难
no one saw what happened in Nevada coming?
因为我们不知道那里有断层线
Because we didn't know there were any fault lines out there.
为什么不知道
Why not?
与主流观点相悖
Contrary to popular belief,
科学家并非无所不知
scientists don't know everything.
我了解到 你曾经公开表示过 有一天
I understand that you publicly stated that, someday,
科学家们 将有能力准确的预测到地震
scientists will be able to predict earthquakes.
事实上 到昨天为止
Well, actually as of yesterday,
我们一直都相信我们可以做出预测
we now believe that we can predict them.
教授
Professor!
能跟你谈谈吗
Talk to you a sec?
好的 很抱歉 失陪一下
Yeah. I'm sorry. Excuse me.
怎么了
What is it?
这是我们监测站的磁脉冲率
Current pulse rates at our monitoring stations.
都沿着圣安德烈亚斯的断层线
All along the San Andreas fault.
平均数值从82增长至85
Their averages are spiking from eighty-two to eighty-five,
峰谷差位于旧金山
with the biggest jumps coming from San Francisco.
比我们在内华达州地震观测到的
More than twenty points higher
要高出20个点
than what we saw in Nevada.
不不不 这不可能
No. No, no, no. There's no way.
我们查了两遍
We checked. We double-checked.
我们重置了所有仪器
Then we reset all the instruments
查了第三遍 结果一样
and triple-checked. Those are the counts.
等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
等等
Wait a minute.
呃
Um...
好的 呃
Okay, uh...
如果 呃
If, uh...
如果我们画一条线 从圣安德烈亚斯底部
If we draw a line from the bottom of the San Andreas
直通到胡佛大坝
up to the hoover dam,
可以发现这条线几乎是沿着科罗拉多河的
it almost literally follows the Colorado river,
而那条河流是自然变形造成的
which is a natural deformation event.
从地理角度看 变形通常发生在大陆板块边缘
And geologically, deformation events mark boundaries.
它们能标记出界限
They mark boundaries.
所以 要是
So, what If...?
要是这一大片土地
What if this whole chunk of land
都与地壳板块相连呢
is connected to our tectonic plate?
那就表示 昨天在内华达州发生的地震
That would tell us that what happened yesterday in Nevada
并非异象
was not an anomaly.
不 如果这是板块运动的开始
No, what if it was a precursor movement
而板块的边界
along the leading edge of the plate boundary fault
从洛杉矶一直延续到旧金山
from Los Angeles all the way up to San Francisco?
你是说
Are you saying you think
整个圣安德烈亚斯断层可能崩塌
the whole San Andreas fault might go off?
没错 我说的就是这个意思
Yes, that's exactly what I'm saying.
我们该通知谁
Who should we call?
通知所有人
Everybody.
哦 真见鬼
Mmm. Oh, bloody hell.
哦 我有纸巾 给你
Oh! I have something. Here.
- 我真是个十足的傻瓜 - 不会啦
- I'm a complete idiot. - No.
非常感谢你 你真好
Thank you very much. It's very kind.
没关系 顺便说一句 我叫布雷克
Yeah, no problem. Um, I'm Blake, by the way.
好的 我 我叫布雷克
Oh, yeah. I'm-I'm Blake.
我不是布雷克 我是本
I'm not Blake! I'm Ben.
我叫本 泰勒 很高兴见到你
Ben Taylor is my name. Pleased to meet you.
很高兴见到你
It's nice to meet you.
刚刚跟你一起来的是你父亲吗
So was that your father you came in with?
丹尼尔 里迪克
Daniel Riddick?
他是我妈妈的男友
Um, he's my mom's boyfriend.
啊
Ah.
你要和他见面吗
Are you meeting with him?
哦 不 我 呃 我还差得远呢
Oh, no. I... uh... not even close.
只是想想罢了 我是来应聘的
I wish. I'm interviewing for a job here
里迪克先生是我未来老板的
and Mr. Riddick is the boss of the boss
老板的老板
of the boss that I'd be working for.
那你是来应聘什么工作的
So, um, what kind of job are you interviewing for?
工程或者设计方面的工作
Anything in engineering or design.
我不挑剔 也不自满
I'm not picky or proud.
我只是 我只是想在这里工作
I just... I just want to work here.
如果你是一个建筑师 这是 呃 这是最理想的地方
If you're an architect, this is the, uh, place to be.
你好 我叫奥利
Hi. I'm Ollie.
他是我哥哥
He's my brother.
你好 很高兴见到你 奥利
Hi. It's nice to meet you, Ollie.
我是布雷克
I'm Blake.
你知道吗 你很漂亮
You know, you're quite beautiful.
谢谢夸奖
Why, thank you.
奥利 你 抱歉
Ollie. Do you...? Sorry.
你记得 你记得我们讨论过的事吗
Do you remember... do you remember what we discussed?
安静地坐好 什么也别说
Sit still and no talking.
很少有人会带弟弟来
It's not normal to bring little brothers
参加面试
to job interviews.
别让我难堪 好吗
And let's not embarrass me, okay?
我可以帮他要你的电话号码吗
Do you mind if I get your phone number for him?
奥利 这真是 你在说什么啊
Ollie! It's exactly... what?!
你肯定不敢问的 接着我就得听你
You'll never ask for it. And then I'll have to listen
没完没了的说 你有多后悔
to how much you regretted not getting it.
泰勒先生
Mr. Taylor?
卡特女士现在可以见你了
Ms. Carter will see you now.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我 呃
I, uh...
祝你好运
Uh... Good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
你坐在这儿
And you, sit here.
不许再乱说话了
And don't say another word.
- 你好 - 我是本
- Hello. - I'm Ben.
我们要马上过去
We're gonna head straight over.
太好了
Excellent.
你想聊点什么
What do you want to talk about?
你是从哪里来的
Um, where you from?
英国
England.
本觉得
Ben thought that while our parents
趁着爸妈在海上旅行
were going to be on a cruise,
我们应该在他面试结束以后
he and I should take a holiday here in the city,
- 在城里玩玩 - 很好
- after his interview. - Awesome.
哦 你想听听看我们的日程安排吗
Oh. Would you like to hear our itinerary?
苏珊
Susan.
很高兴终于能和你见面了
It's nice to finally meet you.
我也是
You as well.
既然丹尼尔已经让你搬去和他一起住了
Now that Daniel's asked you to move in with him,
你们应该都是认真的
things must be pretty serious.
是的
Yes.
你们好 我是拉里萨
Hi. I'm Larissa.
今天由我来为你们服务
I'll be taking care of you today.
我可以介绍一下今天的特色菜吗
Can I tell you about our specials?
好的 我很愿意听你
Please, I'd love to hear what you're...
抱歉 你能过会儿再来吗 拉里萨
Actually, could you come back in a few minutes, Larissa?
好的 没问题
Yeah. Sure.
我听说你之前结过婚
So I understand you've been married before?
呃 是的
Uh, yes.
- 你只有一个女儿 对吗 - 是的
- And you have just the one daughter. Right? - Right.
另一个女儿在事故中淹死了
Your other one drowned in an accident?
是的 你说话很直接
Yes, to put it bluntly.
哦 我不是故意的 我
Oh, I didn't mean it like that. I...
呃 你能等我一下吗
Um, can you just give me one minute?
喂 一切都还好吗？
Hi. Everything okay?
嗯 呃
Yeah, uh...
我正在去维修站的路上 马上就要出发救援了 呃
Oh, I'm on my way to maintenance before we head out, and, uh...
我打扰你了吗
Am I interrupting anything?
不是什么重要的事 怎么了
Nothing important. What's going on?
我只是 我想跟你说声对不起
Look, I just... I wanted to tell you I was sorry
我昨天不应该这么对你
for how I acted yesterday.
真的没关系 雷
No, Ray, really.
不 艾玛 呃 我只是没法突然接受
No, Emma, um, I just wasn't ready to hear
你和布雷克搬去和别人一起住
about you and Blake moving in with someone else.
我 我应该提前告诉你的
I... I should've told you before.
布雷克怎么想
Hey, how's Blake feel about it?
你知道 她还是想让我们一家子团聚的
You know, she'd like us to be a family again.
我 我 我觉得她应该很难
I... I... I think It's gonna be hard for her to...
艾玛
Emma.
- 天啊 - 艾玛
- Oh, my God. - Emma.
这里地震了
We're having an earthquake.
天啊 雷
Oh, Jesus, Ray.
呃 我得离开这里
Uh-uh, I gotta get outta here.
你在哪里
Where are you?
呃 泰特韦斯顿
Um... uh, the Tate weston.
该死 你在顶楼 艾玛 听着
Shit. You're on the top floor. Emma, listen,
把大家叫去楼顶 能叫多少叫多少
get as many people as you can and get to the roof.
我开直升机过来接你 知道了吗
I'm in the helo and I'll get you from there, okay?
知道了
Okay, okay!
好的 去楼顶等我 宝贝
Okay. Get to the roof, honey.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no. No!
到桌子底下去
Under the table.
蹲下 找掩护 坚持住
Drop, cover and hold on!
劳伦斯 里氏级数从6.5跃至8.5
Lawrence, the Richter just jumped from 6.5 to an 8.5.
什么意思
Well, what does that mean?
威力十足
Powers of ten!
是之前的一百倍
So It's a hundred times stronger now!
别担心
Don't worry.
现在加州理工学院应该是最安全的地方
Caltech is probably the safest place to be right now.
教授 看起来整个圣安德烈亚斯的断层线
Professor! It looks like the whole San Andreas fault line
都被激活了
is being activated.
一路向旧金山进发
And It's heading towards San Francisco.
好了 结束了
All right. All done.
好的
Okay.
很高兴认识你 奥利
Well, it was really nice to meet you, Ollie.
祝你在这里玩得愉快
I hope you have fun while you're here.
再见 布雷克 我也很高兴认识你
Bye, Blake. It was nice meeting you, as well.
再见
Goodbye.
哦 我差点忘了
Oh, and, um I almost forgot.
你介意我借一下你的书吗
Do you mind If I borrow your book for a second?
告诉本 我会帮他说好话的
Tell Ben that I'll put in a good word for him.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
我真想赶快到二十岁
I can't wait to be twenty.
- 请上车 - 谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
地震了
It's an earthquake!
快走 带我们离开这里
Well, go, go, go! Get us outta here!
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
走 快走
Go! Hurry, hurry!
好的 快点
Yes! Go, go, go!
我的天啊
Jesus Christ!
见鬼 快走
Oh, shit! Go!
我的腿
My legs!
- 你没事吧 - 天啊
- You okay? - Oh, my God.
他 他死了 他
He's... he's dead! He...
- 布雷克 布雷克 布雷克 - 他死了
- Blake? Blake? Blake. - He's dead.
你还好吗 受伤了吗
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
没 没有 我应该没受伤
N... no... no, I don't think... I don't think so.
但我的腿被卡住了
But my legs are stuck.
快点
Come on.
好 好
Okay. Okay.
我会把你带出去的 好吗?
We're gonna get you outta here. Okay?
噢 天啊 好吧
Oh, God. Okay.
快想 快想想
Think. Think.
丹尼尔?
Daniel?
布雷克 我去找人帮忙
Blake, I'm gonna go for help.
- 不 丹尼尔 - 我很快回来
- No, Daniel... - I'll be right back.
- 我很快回来 - 不 丹尼尔 别
- I'll be right back. - No, Daniel. Don't.
别丢下我一个人
Please don't leave me alone!
丹尼尔! 不 丹尼尔
Daniel! No, Daniel.
赶快撤离!
Keep moving!
快 快点! 我们走 救命!
Come on. Hurry! Let's go! Help!
救命啊! 快走!
Help! Keep moving!
快走! 我们走! 救命!
Keep moving! Let's go! Help!
有个女孩困在车里了!
There's a girl trapped in a town car!
- 在哪? - 停车场
- Where? - In the parking garage!
来帮帮忙吧 噢 天啊
You gotta come help. Oh, God!
起来! 起来!
Get up! Get up!
快离开大楼 到外面去!
Out of the building! Get outside!
里迪克先生! 里迪克先生?
Mr. Riddick! Mr. Riddick?
里迪克先生!
Mr. Riddick!
救我!
Help me!
快! 快!
Come on! Come on!
快跑
Move it.
布雷克
Blake.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
苏珊! 艾玛!
Susan! Emma!
苏珊! 我们去屋顶!
Susan! We gotta get to the roof!
离开这儿!
We've gotta get out of here!
不! 这边
No! This way!
别挡路!
Get out of my way!
苏珊! 苏珊!
Susan! Susan!
噢 天啊! 啊!
Oh, God! Aaah!
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
这边! 出口在这里!
This way! Get over here!
- 女士 我们快跑! - 好 好
- Ma'am, we got to go! - Okay. Okay.
快走 快走!
Keep moving! Keep moving!
拉里萨!
Larissa!
拉里萨 跟我走!
Larissa, you have to come with me!
我们得到楼顶上去
We've gotta get to the roof!
各位!
Everybody!
救 救援直升机马上就到
There-there's a rescue helicopter coming!
等等 要往上走!
Wait! We've gotta go up!
噢 天哪 天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
雷 你要快点来
Ray, you better be right about this.
雷
Ray.
哇
Whoa!
噢
Oh!
噢 天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Uh...
去那边!
Up there!
噢 该死
Oh, shit.
快点 艾玛 快 我们没时间了
Come on, Emma. Come on. We gotta go.
艾玛 快跑!
Emma, run!
艾玛
Emma.
雷!
Ray!
艾玛!
Emma!
我抓住你了!
I got you!
噢 雷
Oh, Ray.
艾玛 有没有受伤?
Emma, are you hurt?
嗯...
Um...
- 你受伤了吗? - 我想没有
- Are you hurt? - I don't think so.
好 会没事的 但是听好
Okay. It's gonna be okay, but listen.
我们必须离开这
We gotta get outta here.
你到前排左边位置坐好
I need you to get to the front left seat.
- 我马上来 好吗? - 好的
- I'll be right there. Okay? - Okay.
该死!
Shit!
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
噢 天哪
Oh, God.
- 雷! - 抓紧了!
- Ray! - Hold on!
救命! 来人救救我!
Help! Somebody help me!
救命! 有人吗!
Help! Somebody help!
- 我是雷 - 爸爸 快救我!
- This is Ray. - Dad, please help!
布雷克 怎么了?
Blake, what's wrong?
一场强震!
In a huge earthquake!
丹尼尔不知道哪去了
I don't know where Daniel went.
我被困在车库的轿车里
I'm stuck in a limo in a garage.
爸爸! 我真的好害怕
I'm really, really scared, dad!
你受伤了吗 宝贝?
Baby, are you hurt?
没有...
No...
布雷克! 该死
Blake! Goddamn it.
怎么了? 什么情况?
What? What is it?
该死 她手机信号中断了
Shit. Her cell service just went out.
救援人员不会那么快
There's no way rescue personnel are gonna be
赶到车库去救她
diggin' in garages any time soon.
还有很多人员聚集在地面上等待救援
Too many populated places above ground.
那... 呃... 我们该怎么办?
What, uh... What are we gonna do?
去救我们女儿
We're going to get our daughter.
布雷克! 布雷克!
Blake! Blake!
救命 我在这!
H-help! I'm over here!
布雷克! 布雷克 我是本 你没事吧?
Blake! Blake, It's Ben. Are you okay?
我出不去 楼顶在塌陷
I can't get out. The roof's collapsing.
我的腿被卡住了
My legs are trapped.
好 好
O-okay. Okay.
奥利 我们把石块撬开
Oh, Ollie, we need to lift this beam
让她的腿可以活动
to get the pressure off her legs.
- 好吗? - 好的
- Okay? - Yeah.
试试这个
Oh, let's try this.
好 准备好没有?
Okay, ready? Ready?
一 二 三
One, two, three.
加油 奥利
Come on, Ollie.
用尽全力
Give it everything you've got.
我在使劲!
I am!
起作用了!
It's working!
奥利!
Ollie!
本? 奥利?
Ben? Ollie?
我们在 我们在呢
We're still here. We're still here.
噢不 不
Oh, no. No.
你们快逃出去吧
You guys have to get out of here.
这里马上就要塌了
This building's gonna collapse.
不
No.
不可能
There's not a chance in hell
我们绝不会把你丢下的
we're leaving you in there.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
好了 用这个
All right. Here we go.
太棒了 起作用了!
Brilliant. It's working!
撑到最高了
It won't go any higher.
我还是出不来!
I'm still stuck!
啊!
Ah!
奥利! 她动了!
Ollie! She's moving!
快 快 快
Hurry, hurry. Hurry!
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
- 没事 - 你确定?
- Yeah. - Are you sure?
是的
Yeah.
谢谢 谢谢你们
Thank you. Thank you, guys.
乐意效劳
Pleasure.
干得漂亮
Good job.
快走 余震又来了
Come on. It's another aftershock.
- 我们快离开这 - 好的
- We've got to get out of here. Okay!
小心! 快点 快!
Look out! Hurry! Come on!
快离开这里
We have to get away from these buildings.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
布雷克! 这边 走这边!
Blake! This way! This way!
上帝啊 我的天!
Jesus! Oh, my God!
奥利! 布雷克!
Ollie! Blake!
快! 走 走!
Come on! Go! Go!
真想不到丹尼尔会扔下我不管
I cannot believe that Daniel just took off.
真是个混蛋
What an asshole.
请路上的人让开 让开
Step aside, people.
我得尽快联系我父母
I gotta get ahold of my parents.
让他们知道我没事
I gotta let them know I'm okay.
电话打不通 我试过了
Cellphones aren't working. I've tried.
我们得找一家电器商店
We need to find an electronics store.
你们的书上有购物指南吗?
Does that book of yours list businesses?
我的书里什么都有
My book has everything.
好消息是 我们大部分的应急系统
The good news is most of our emergency systems
还在运作 在这里
are still working. Here.
我们从17个监控器中检测到了信号
We've got signals coming in from seventeen monitors.
我们刚刚经历了一场9.1级强震
We just experienced a 9.1.
劳伦斯... 来看看这个
Lawrence... You need to see this.
获取到什么了?
What do we got?
这是震前采集的波频率数据
Here are the pulse rates before the quake.
好的
Yeah, okay.
这是目前的波频率
And here are the pulse rates now.
相同
The same.
甚至更高
Or higher.
所以地震并没有减弱
So the earthquake didn't diminish them.
噢 天哪
Oh, man.
噢 情况不妙
Oh, this is not good.
阿列克谢 把所有还在断层上运作的监测站数据
Alexi, I want all the data from every monitoring station
现在全部汇报给我
still up along the fault line and get it for me now.
- 好的 - 出什么事了?
- Right. - What's going on?
该死
Shit.
噢 天 都摔坏掉了
Oh, man. This thing's fried.
快点 我需要所有人的帮忙
Come on. I need everybody.
- 我们要做什么? - 让你来广播
- W-what are we doing? - Gettin' you on the air.
我们要通知所有人
We need to warn people.
要怎么做? 信号都中断了
How? There's no way to upload a signal.
这里可是加州理工学院
You're at Caltech.
好了 你们谁想在独立研究课上得A?
Okay, who wants an A in independent study?
我开一门新课:
I'm startin' a new class:
"如何通过入侵电视台来拯救人类"
"How to save lives by hacking media outlets."
哦不错 我参加
Hell yeah, man. I'm in.
很好 带上笔记本电脑 出发
Sweet, bro. Get your laptop. Let's go.
在这边 快快快
Right here. Move, move, move.
好了 起
Here we go. Up. Lift.
应该不远了
It should be just up ahead.
就在那儿
There it is.
好 任何需要靠电运作的东西都不能用
Okay, anything running on electricity isn't gonna work,
所以我们要找一个拨盘的或者按键的电话
so we have to find a rotary or a push button phone.
你怎么知道这些的?
How do you know all this?
我爸爸教我的 他在洛杉矶消防局工作
My dad. He works for L.A. fire and rescue.
在这呢
Over here.
太好了 我找找通讯线
Great. I'll look for a landline.
找到了!
I got one!
爸爸
Dad.
爸爸 我出来了 我没事
Dad. I got out. I'm okay.
她没事
She's okay.
让我和她说说话
Oh. Let me talk to her.
布雷克?
Blake?
妈妈?
Mom?
噢 感谢上帝 亲爱的
Oh, thank God, honey.
丹尼尔还好吗?
Is Daniel okay?
他丢下我跑了 妈妈
He left me, mom.
他怎么了?
He what?
他告诉保安我的位置
He told a security guard where I was
然后就丢下我不管了
and then he just took off
有一对兄弟听到了谈话
and these two brothers that I met overheard him
就赶过来救了我
and they came to help me.
我现在和他们在一起
I'm with them right now.
他把她丢下了
He left her?!
我们这就过去接你 亲爱的 你在哪?
We're comin' to get you, honey. Where are you?
我在唐人街的一家电器店里
I'm in an-an electronics store in Chinatown.
亲爱的 会没事的
Honey, It's gonna be okay
但是你听我说
but I need you to listen to me.
快出去
Getting outta there
那边马上就会堵得死死的
is gonna be a complete gridlock nightmare,
到高地上去 那里更安全
so get to higher ground. It's safer.
- 也方便我能看见你 - 好的
- That's where I'm gonna be able to see you. - Okay.
还记得周末我们给马洛里过生日的地方吗?
Do you remember where we spent Mallory's birthday weekend?
科伊特塔?
At Coit tower?
是的 就是山上那座
Yeah. That-that tall
- 高高的水泥喷嘴一样的建筑 - 没错
- cement nozzle thing on the hill. - Exactly.
别停下 直接过去
Don't stop anywhere. Go there.
我们在那见
That's where We'll meet.
坚强 宝贝 我们这就来接你
Stay strong, honey. We're comin' to get you.
好的 等下 妈妈
Okay. Wait, mom. Mom.
你和爸爸怎么在一起?
How-how are you and dad together?
以后再解释 好吗宝贝?
We'll explain later. Okay, honey?
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你们 再见
I love you guys. Bye.
你好 我是丹尼尔
Hi, you've reached Daniel.
有事请留言 我会尽快回复
Please leave me a message and I'll get back to you.
你竟敢把我女儿扔下不管了?
You left my daughter?
如果你没死 我会过去亲手宰了你
If you're not already dead, I'm gonna fuckin' kill you.
干得好
Thatta girl.
好了 我们得离开这
All right, we need to get going.
那你爸爸怎么来接我们?
So how is your dad going to pick us up?
他驾驶直升机 正赶过来
He's on his way in a helicopter.
真是太酷了
That's so cool.
我需要你们帮我在地图上找到科伊特塔
I need you to look up Coit tower on your map.
轮到你打电话了
It's your turn.
你们的父母一定很担心
Your parents will be worried sick.
谢谢你
Thank you.
待在路面上
Stay on the street.
我们去哪儿?
Where are we going?
别挡路!
Get out of my way!
嘿! 那是我的地盘!
Hey! That was my spot!
你知道吗 你和布雷克通话的时候
You know, when you were talking to Blake
那是马洛里走了之后
that was the first time I heard you say Mallory's name
我第一次听你提到马洛里的名字
since we lost her.
你记得我们在旧金山旅游的时候的照片吗?
Hey, do you know that Blake keeps pictures
布雷克一直留着
from our San Francisco trip?
记得 在她的回忆盒里
Yeah, in her memory box.
真想不到 我们有一天还会回到那里去
It's ironic. Us heading back up there.
那一次很开心的旅行
It was a fun trip.
我们在哪?
Where are we?
贝克斯菲尔德 已经是一片废墟了
Bakersfield. Or what's left of it.
离旧金山大概还有90分钟的航程
We're just about ninety minutes from San Francisco.
雷?!
Ray?!
你关掉引擎了吗?
Did you just turn off the engine?
是的 我们的变速装置出故障了
Yeah, we got a gearbox failure.
肯定是刚才在洛杉矶撞到的
Must've been that hit we took in L.A.
现在只能自行降落了
I'm gonna have to auto rotate down.
自什么?
A-auto-what?
撞到地上
We're gonna crash.
- 好 好吧 - 抓紧了
- Right. Okay. - Hold on.
开始了
Here we go.
抓紧!
Hold on!
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
要到了 要到了
Almost there. Almost there.
就在那里降落
Just gonna set it down right here.
我们身上都是燃料 快点从这里出去
We got fuel all over us. We need to get outta here.
快点 离开
Come on. We gotta go.
- 低下身子 - 好的
- Stay low. Stay low. - Okay.
没事的 我们继续走
It's okay. We just gotta keep movin'.
继续往前 好
Just gotta keep movin'. All right.
给我!
Give it to me!
不! 这是我的!
No! It's mine!
快 快 快
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
进去 进去
Get in, get in, get in, get in.
这车好像是偷来的
Looks like It's been stolen.
好 我们再偷一次
All right. Well, We'll steal it again.
雷
Ray.
冷静点
Easy.
我需要那辆卡车
I'll be needin' that truck.
今天可不行
Not today.
哦 天呐
Oh, my God.
这次地震
The quake centered
以洛杉矶市中心东部二十英里处为中心
about twenty Miles east of downtown Los Angeles.
信号塔都毁了
Cell towers are down.
城里的大部分电力也中断了
Most of the city's electricity, down.
通讯处于停滞状态
Communication at a virtual standstill.
对加利福尼亚南部地区
The devastation to Southern California
造成了灾难性的破坏
is expected to be massive.
事实上 整个州都受到影响
In fact, the entire state will take a hit.
- 我们已经收到有关建筑物塌陷的报道 - 我们进去了
- We're already getting reports of collapsed buildings - We're in.
- 北至旧金山和海湾地区 - 太棒了
- As far north as San Francisco and the surrounding bay area. - Yes.
至少已经发生过五次余震了
There have been at least five aftershocks.
好的 我们开始了
Okay. Here we go.
制片人告诉我们
Uh, producers are telling us
我们有来自洛杉矶的首次现场直播
we have our first live feed from Los Angeles.
拍摄开始 五 四...
We're rolling. Five, four...
塞雷娜・约翰逊现在正在
Serena Johnson is on the ground
加利福尼亚工学院地震学中心现场
at the seismology center at caltech.
你好 克里斯
Hello, Chris.
现在坐在我身边的是
I'm here with Dr. Lawrence Hayes,
加利福尼亚工学院地震研究室执行理事劳伦斯・海耶斯教授
executive director for earthquake studies at caltech.
他和他的研究伙伴基姆帕克博士
He and his research partner, Dr. Kim park,
设计出了一个可以预测地震的理论模型
have come up with a model that predicts earthquakes.
他们预测到洛杉矶会发生地震
They knew L.A. was going to get hit.
可是没有人理会他们
But nobody listened to them.
现在让我们一起来听听吧 请说吧 教授
It's time now to listen. Go ahead, doctor.
好的 用地震学术语来说
Okay. Um, in seismology terms,
我们现在所经历的叫做地震群体事件
what we're experiencing is what we call a swarm event.
基本上来说 加利福尼亚
Um, basically, California's
整个地壳构造板块都移动了
entire tectonic plate has shifted.
目前看来 我们在洛杉矶
Yes, it seems the quake we experienced here
发生的地震 一路蔓延
in Los Angeles did major damage
对旧金山造成了极大的破坏
all the way up in San Francisco.
是的 不过他们感受到的地震
Yeah. Yeah, but the earthquake that they felt
来自中央谷
was from movement along the fault line
断层线的活动
in the central valley.
而尾部的断层线还没有开始移动
Their end of the fault line has not moved yet.
更重要的是 大家必须知道
Uh, more importantly, people need to know
地震尚未结束
that the shaking is not over.
我说的地震 而不是余震
And It's not aftershocks I'm talking about.
旧金山还会再次发生地震
San Francisco will get hit again.
而且会比这次的更加严重
And It's going to be a bigger monster this time.
我们的样机预测震级至少是9.5
Our models are predicting a 9.5 or greater.
震动会极为强烈 即便是在加利福尼亚
It will be so big that even though It's happening
发生的地震
here in California
你在东海岸也会有震感
you will feel it on the east coast.
所以 我在这里要郑重的提醒
Now, I cannot emphasize this enough
旧金山的人们
to the people of San Francisco:
你们得马上离开 就现在
You need to get out. And I mean now.
如若来不及的话 你们需要
And, If you can't, you need to find
找到任何何以掩护或者抓牢的东西
any means possible to drop cover and hold on.
因为你们能不能活下来全靠它了
Because your life is gonna depend on it.
愿上帝与你们同在
God be with you.
余震依旧
Aftershocks continue
摇晃着洛杉矶地区
to rock the Los Angeles area...
你有没有想过 要是没有失去马洛里的话
You ever think about what our life would be like.
我们的生活会是什么样
If we hadn't lost mallory?
专家们建议大家...
People are advised to...
艾玛 别这样
Em, don't.
我想过 每时每刻都在想
I do. All the time.
我们已经向前看了
We've moved on.
不 我们没有
No, we didn't move on.
我们停在了那个时刻
We stopped moving.
她又不是因为你没有看好而死去的
You didn't lose her on your watch.
确实 但是我失去她了
No. But I lost her.
我们能不讨论这个吗
Can we not talk about this?
你欠我的
You owe it to me.
又是这样
This!
自从她死了你几乎每天都是这样
This is the most I've gotten out of you since she died.
我真的想知道 雷
I need to know, Ray.
是因为我吗 是我做了什么吗
Was... was it me? What did I do?
因为我从没怪过你
Because I never blamed you.
我不想谈这个
I don't wanna talk about it.
我 这还有什么关系呢 她都不在了
I... it doesn't matter. She's gone.
现在你也离开了
Now you're gone.
还有什么意义呢
What's the point?
我觉得问题在于
I guess the point is
这就是我没留下的原因
this is why I didn't stick around.
听起来是极其严重的情况 劳丽
Sounds like a terrible situation there, Laurie.
我知道当时一定很艰难...
I know that it must have been very difficult...
嗨 注意 小心
Hey! Look out! Watch out!
嗨 嗨 快停下
Hey! Hey! You have to stop!
雷
Ray!
这是什么情况
What is this?
圣安德烈亚斯断层
The San Andreas fault.
我说过我们该走另一条路的
I told you we should've gone the other way.
因为你预测到了会发生这个吗
Because you knew this was gonna happen?
哦
Oh.
你
You!
我们真的非常感激你们
We owe you guys a huge thanks.
不必了
No need.
我们差点也犯了同样的错
We nearly made the same mistake ourselves
不过我们驶离道路的时候爆了个车轴
but busted an axle when we ran off the road.
多亏我视力比他的好
Thank goodness my eyes are better'n his.
请问这里有路能绕过去吗
Do you know If there's any way around this?
这个嘛 198号公路可能还行
Well, uh... the one-ninety-eight might not be out.
- 刚好能绕过去 - 有多远呢
- Through the pass. - How far is that?
你们得掉个头走 大概七十英里
Oh, ya gotta backtrack, maybe, seventy Miles or so.
先生 冒昧问一句
Sir, If you don't mind me Askin'...
你的帽子是哪来的
Where'd you get your hat?
你们可真帮了我们大忙了
You guys really bailed us out.
真的不用我们送你们去哪吗
You sure we can't fly you anywhere?
不用了 我们儿子住在山上
Yeah. Our son lives in the mountains.
那里可没地方能降落
There's no place to land.
多谢你的车了
Thanks for the wheels. You bet.
路上小心 拜
Be safe. Bye.
再过几分钟油就加满了
We should be fueled up in a couple of minutes.
好啊 太好了
Okay, great.
你还好吧
Everything okay?
你刚才问我是不是因为你
You asked me before If it was you.
其实不是
It wasn't.
我知道你不怪我
I knew you didn't blame me.
我...我只是不知道该怎么面对马洛里的死
I... I just didn't know how to deal with Mallory's death.
那天带马洛里去漂流是我的主意
It was my idea to take mallory rafting that day.
雷
Ray.
你不该这样责怪自己
You can't blame yourself for what happened.
可当出事的是自己的孩子时感觉真的太难过了
It's just different when It's your own kid.
我知道
I know.
- 爸爸 - 马洛里
- Dad! - Mallory!
有时候 我无法把她当时看我的表情从脑海里挥去
Sometimes I can't get that look she had outta my head.
就是那一刻
The moment she realized
她意识到我救不了她
that... I wasn't gonna be able to save her.
然后每天回家面对你和布雷克
And then coming home every day to you and Blake
只会使之变得更难
only made it harder.
因为我们再也回不到从前了
Because nothin' was the way it used to be.
而我们的从前...
And the way it used to be was...
是那么完美
It was perfect.
我本该对你敞开心扉的
I should've let you in.
我只是不知道该怎么做
I just didn't know how.
而我们之间却这样结束了 我很抱歉 艾玛
I'm so sorry for how things ended with us, em.
我真的很抱歉
I really am.
若是连你都救不了我们的女儿...
If you couldn't save our daughter...
其他人更不行
Then nobody could have.
我真的很想她
I miss her so much.
我也是
Me, too.
去救我们的女儿吧
Let's go get our daughter.
快走啊 继续走
Let's go! Keep it movin'!
快走 加油 快走
Let's go! Come on. Let's go.
顺着疏散路线走
Follow the evacuation route.
再走几条街就到伦巴第街道
Just a few more blocks to Lombard Avenue,
然后就能直接到科伊特塔
which leads to Coit tower.
我能问问
Do you mind If I ask
你为什么戴着两条一样的项链吗
why you wear two of the same necklaces?
呃...
Um...
其中一条是我妹妹的
One of them used to be my sister's.
我... 自从她去世后我就开始把它戴上了
I, uh... I started wearing it after she died.
在那场事故发生的前一年
We had given them to each other
这是我们送给彼此的圣诞礼物
for Christmas the year before.
我... 我很抱歉 我... 我不是有意...
I'm... I'm so sorry. I... I didn't mean...
没关系的 我并没打算掩饰什么
No. It's okay. I'm... I'm not hiding them.
嗨 快看呐
Hey. Check it out.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
他们应该有个电源箱的
They should have a supply box.
里面有我们用得上的东西
It'll have stuff that we can use.
是这个吗
Is this it?
没错
Yes!
好 看着
Oh, okay. There we go.
每个城市都有一个现场急救员
Every city has a tactical channel
用来通话用的火灾指挥用频道
that first responders use to communicate on.
我们可以留着听最新动态
We can listen in and we can see what's going on.
好 拿着这些
Okay. Here. Take these.
好的
Yeah.
拿着这个
Take this.
- Mre是什么 - 就是应急食品
- What's an mre? - Meals ready-to-eat.
这些东西有三年以上的保质期
These things have a shelf life of over three years.
尝起来不怎么样
Wow. They don't taste so good.
酷
Cool.
布雷克
Blake!
我觉得我们可能去不了
I think we're going to have a problem
你说的那个喷嘴样的地方了
with that big nozzle thing you were talking about.
什么 你在说什么
What? What do you mean?
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
我们得启用B计划
We have to go to plan B.
我们好像没有B计划吧
I didn't think we had one.
现在有了
We do now.
我们得去另外一个最高的地方
We need to get to the next highest ground
给我爸爸发信号
so that we can signal my dad
所以我们要去诺布山
in the helicopter. That would be Nob Hill.
那是市里最高的地方
It's the highest point in the city.
在另一边
It's the other way.
走吧
Okay. Come on!
布雷克 等一下 等一下
Bl-no. Blake, wait! Wait! Just... just wait.
借过 让一让 让一让
Coming through. Move, move, move.
布雷克 只有我们在往那个方向去
Blake, we'd be the only ones going that way.
我爸爸说去最高的地方
My dad said to get to higher ground,
那我们就去最高的地方
so that's what we gotta do.
可... 要是他来不了怎么办
But... what If he doesn't make it?
我知道这听起来可能有点疯狂
Listen, I know that this sounds crazy.
不过你得相信他一定会来的
But you have to trust me that he will.
我... 我...
I... I c...
本
Ben.
你知道按键式电话能和
Did you know about the push-button phone
陆线连接起来用吗
working with the landline?
电源箱
The supply box?
火灾指挥用频道
Tactical radio channels?
我真觉得我们应该和她一起
I really think we should stick with her.
好吧 看来我们是要去诺布山了
Okay. Looks like we're going to Nob Hill.
好的 走吧
Okay. Let's go.
这条信息是加利福尼亚
The following message is transmitted at the request
应急管理部门要求发送的
of the California emergency management.
请居民们立刻撤离
Residents are encouraged to evacuate immediately.
看来整个城市都在撤离
Looks like the whole city's evacuating.
艾玛 机场好像去不了了
Em, we got a problem at the airport.
那我们能从哪里降落
Where are we gonna land?
没办法了
We can't.
至少不能在城市里降
At least, not in the city.
跟我来
Come with me.
哦... 好的
Uh... okay.
你不是开玩笑的吧
You gotta be kidding me.
艾玛 我们现在没地方降落了
Em, we have no place to set this plane down
我们必须尽可能的靠近科伊特塔
and we have to get as close to Coit tower as we possibly can.
三分钟内 我们就会飞到内河码头上方
In three minutes, we're gonna be over the embarcadero.
然后呢
And?
然后我们跳到At&t运动场里去
And, we're gonna drop into AT&T park.
可我不会跳伞
But I don't know how to parachute.
没关系 我们双人串联跳伞
That's okay. We're gonna tandem-jump.
我 我我觉得还是待在飞机里比较好
I-I-I think we should just stay with the plane.
飞机一旦耗尽燃油
The plane's gonna nosedive in the pacific
就会直接俯冲掉到太平洋里
as soon as it runs out of gas.
那好吧
Okay. Mm.
相信我
Trust me.
我的天
Oh, my God!
准备好了吗
You ready?
- 我像准备好的样子吗 - 那是
- Do I sound ready?! - Yep!
我有好久没没让你上二垒了
It's been a while since I got you to second base.
随着劳伦斯・海耶斯博士的沉重警告
With a grave warning from Dr. Lawrence Hayes
在电视广播上播出
blanketing the airwaves...
旧金山已开始实施撤退方案
San Francisco has begun evacuation procedures.
海岸巡逻队希望任何一个有船只的人士
The coast guard is asking anyone with access to a boat
都能参与其中...
to will please volunteer in the process...
断层线的活动
fault line in the central valley.
而断层线的尾部还没有开始移动
Their end of the fault line has not moved yet.
旧金山还会再次发生地震
San Francisco is going to get hit again,
而且会比这次的更加严重
and this will be a much bigger monster.
我真希望所有人都听到了我们的预警
I hope we've given everyone enough warning.
这真是破天荒头一次
Would be the first of its kind.
这就是你说的吗
This is it, isn't it?
此时此刻 我希望我是错的
Right now, I wanna be so wrong.
大家快找掩体
Everyone, take cover!
这很快就会结束的
This will be over soon here.
为旧金山的人们祈祷吧
But pray for the people of San Francisco.
你知道吗 nob是个俚语
Did you know "nob" is a slang term
意思是富裕 富有
which means "rich" or "wealthy".
是"Nobility"贵族的简写
"It's a shortened version of the word 'nobility',
因为住在这里的都是富有家庭
because of the families that live there.
这里又被称为斯诺希尔
It is also derisively known as 'snob hill'."
怎么了
what is it?
丹尼尔造的那座建筑
Daniel built that building.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
我操
Oh, shit.
快走 快走
Move! Move!
走啊 奥利
Come on, Ollie!
奥利
Ollie!
我想回家
I want to go home now!
坚持住
Just hold on!
一会就好 我保证
It's gonna be okay. I promise!
他们在那里会丧命的
They're gonna get killed out there.
艾玛 到体育场的边上去
Em, get to the side of the stadium.
我马上就回来 我马上就回来
I'll be right there. I'll be right there!
这里不安全 到体育场的边上去
It's not safe here. Get to the side of the stadium!
马上到体育场的边上去
Go to the side of the stadium right now!
这座楼要塌了 快走啊
This building's gonna collapse. You need to move!
赶快 赶紧离开街道
Hurry! You gotta get off the street!
到体育场的边上去 快啊
Get to the side of the stadium! Right now!
体育场的边上去 到体育场的边上去
Side of the stadium. Get to the side of the stadium!
快点 快点 快离开街道
Come on. Come on. Come on. Off the street!
去体育场 到体育场的边上去
Get to the stadium. Side of the stadium!
快点 离开街道
Come on! Get out of the street!
没事的 有我在
It's all right! I got you.
有我在 起
I got you. And up!
- 这边 雷 - 带上她
- Over here, Ray! - Take her.
- 带上她 艾玛 - 好的
- Here. Take her, em. - I got her!
你会没事的 你会没事的
You're gonna be okay. You're gonna be okay.
会没事的
It's all right.
大家都蹲下
Everybody down!
大家都好吧 有没有人受伤
Everybody okay? Anybody hurt?
没有
No.
艾玛 你没事吧
Emma. You okay?
没事
Yeah.
你是怎么知道这里安全的
How'd you know we'd be safe?
因为我们躲在一个坚固的东西边上
Just get up against something sturdy.
想要保护好自己
Protect yourself.
就要寻找地震活命三角区
Triangle of life.
地震活命三角区是由加拿大人道格-库普提出的一种理论，
是指地震发生后，室内的人应该躲在大而坚实的物体旁，
这样墙体和梁倒下后能与该物体形成一个三角空间，
躲在这个空间里的人便可活命
走吧
Let's go.
她会平安无事的
She's gonna be okay.
但我们要怎样才能横穿过去呢
But how do we get through that?
我们不横穿过去 我们绕过去
We don't. We go around it.
嗷
Oh.
好了
Oh, okay.
我们得把这个碎片取出来
We have to get that out of there.
如果继续带着它前进的话 伤势会加重的
If you try walking with it, it could cause more damage.
这会很疼的 你准备好了吗
This is gonna hurt. Are you ready?
啊 啊
Gah! Ahh.
本
Ben!
没事儿 我没事儿
I'm all right. I'm all right.
你觉得你还能继续前进吗
Do you think you could put some weight on it?
我们得接着走 我们还得爬过那座山
We have to keep moving. We gotta get up that hill.
行
Yeah.
好的 来吧
Okay. Here.
这次地震究竟有多强烈
How bad did they get hit?
九点六级
9.6.
有史以来最强烈的一次地震
Largest quake in recorded history.
噢 不
Oh, no.
这儿已经烧了一阵子了
Coit's been burning a while.
她肯定逃到别的地方去了
She's gone someplace else.
宝贝 你在哪儿呢 在哪儿呢
Now, where are you, baby? Where are you?
你的B计划是什么
What's your plan b?
噢 该死的
Oh, shit.
怎么了
What's happening?
我们得赶紧走
We gotta go.
海水的波动表明海啸即将来袭
Water being pulled out like that's a Tsunami.
我们得离开这个港湾 赶快
We gotta get outta the bay, now.
等等 等等 等一下
Wait. Wait, wait a second,
- 让我歇一下 - 让你休息一下吧
- just give me one second. - Give you a second.
天啦
God!
气象部门刚对加州中部和北部的沿海地区
The weather service has issued a Tsunami warning
发布了海啸预警
for coastal areas of northern and central California,
包括马林郡 纳帕
including the following Marin, napa,
旧金山 蒙特里等城市
San Francisco and Monterey.
快 我们得赶快走
Come on, guys. We gotta go!
快走 我们得赶快走
We gotta go! We gotta move fast!
我们得去丹尼尔那座写字楼
We gotta get to Daniel's building.
雷
Ray.
我看到了
I see it!
好吧 抓紧了
All right, hold on!
我们得在它达到浪峰之前穿过去
We gotta get over it before it crests!
快啊 快啊
Come on! Come on!
我们可以的 我们能行的
We're gonna make it. We're gonna make it!
噢 他妈的
Oh, shit!
雷
Ray!
见鬼了
Shit.
这是什么动静
What's that noise?
我们的位置还是不够高
We're not high enough.
趴...趴下 趴下 快躲起来
Get... get down! Get down! Take cover!
抓紧了 奥利
Hold on tight, Ollie!
啊 啊
Ah! Ah!
噢 啊
Uh! Aah!
本
Ben!
奥利
Ollie.
水势还在上涨
The water's still rising.
我们还得往上走
We have to get higher.
这边
This way!
本
Ben.
奥利 来 抓紧了
Ollie, come. Grab on.
噢 我的天啦
Oh, my God.
她会在哪儿呢 雷
Where is she, Ray?
她是个聪敏的孩子
She's a smart girl.
她肯定会找个高处躲起来
She'd know to head for one of these high-rises.
嗯
Hm.
我们一定得找到她
We just gotta find her.
你还好吧
Are you all right?
让我们来检查一下你腿上的伤势
We need to take a look at that leg.
奥利 看能找到点什么东西
Okay. Ollie, see If there's something
我们可以用来做绷带
that we can use as a bandage.
再看看能不能找到点干净的水
And see If you can find clean water.
好的
Yeah.
好拉
Okay.
好拉 让我们看看情况怎么样
Okay. Let's see what we're dealing with here.
怎么了
What?
你实在太...太不可思议了
You're absolutely... Unbelievable.
老妈肯定会喜欢她的
Mum's going to love her.
我找到几条毛巾
There are a few towels in here.
噢 太好了
Oh, great.
我再去找点水
I'll look for some water.
跳过来 快
Just jump! Come on!
我接住你了
I got you.
嘿 我看到有人驾着船
Hey! I can see some people in a boat!
不会吧 不会吧
No way. No way!
那是我父母
Those are my parents!
妈妈 爸爸
Mom! Dad!
- 妈妈 - 救命啊
- Mom! - Help!
爸爸 嘿
Dad! Hey!
爸爸 妈妈
Dad! Mom!
妈妈
Mom!
他们听不到我们
They can't hear us.
怎么了
What?
艾玛 如果再找不到她
Em, If we don't get to her soon,
我们就快要没油了
we're gonna need some gas.
我们还有大概一个小时 最多一个半小时的油量
We got maybe an hour, hour and a half tops before we...
- 雷 - 怎么啦
- Ray. - Yeah?
先停一下
H-hold on.
噢 天啦 噢 我的上帝啊 那是布雷克
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, It's Blake!
- 噢 我的天啦 - 艾玛
- Oh, my God! - Emma!
我们终于找到她了
We found her.
布雷克
Blake!
奥利
Ollie!
奥利 奥利
Ollie! Ollie!
奥利
Ollie!
我抓住你了 我抓住你了
I've got you! I've got you!
布雷克在哪儿
Where's Blake?
她在后面
She's back there!
待在这儿别动 奥利
Stay here, Ollie.
布雷克
Blake!
Blake! Bla...
不 不 不
no! No! No!
这栋楼在下沉 我们得赶紧走
The building's sinking! We have to move.
我们得往上走
We have to move up.
快走 奥利 快
Come on, Ollie, hurry!
噢 不 不 不 我的天啦 布雷克
No, no, no, no. Oh, my God, Blake!
艾玛 你来驾驶这艘船
Em, take the wheel.
我看到了一个入口 我去找她
I see a way in. I'm going after her.
雷
Ray!
我会把她带回来的
I'm bringin' her back.
我保证
I promise.
布雷克
Blake!
爸爸
Dad!
- 不要害怕 - 那个门被锁住了
- Don't worry. - The door's blocked!
布雷克 不要害怕 我会把你救出去的
Blake, don't worry. I'm gonna get you outta here.
好吗 我会救你出来的
Okay? I'm gettin' you out!
爸爸 我好害怕
Daddy, I'm scared.
我快要窒息了
I'm running out of air!
爸爸 我觉得我不行了
Daddy, I don't think I can do this.
布雷克 坚持住 坚持住
Blake, you hold on, hold on!
这边
There!
本 我不希望布雷克死
Ben, I don't want Blake to die.
她不会死的
She's not going to die.
我这就回去救她 好嘛
I'm going back for her. Okay?
但我要你好好地待在这儿
But I need you to stay here.
好嘛
Okay?
乖
Good boy.
奥利
Ollie!
本
Ben!
奥利 到我背上来 到我背上来
On my back! On my back, Ollie!
布雷克会死的
Blake's going to die.
是不是
Isn't she?
爸爸
Dad.
没事儿的
All right.
爸爸
Dad.
我爱你 爸爸
I love you, dad.
请 请转告...
And please, please tell...
请转告妈妈 我也爱她
Please tell mom that I love her, too.
布雷克 不要放弃
Blake, don't you quit on me!
爸爸 我很抱歉 爸爸
Daddy. I'm sorry, dad.
布雷克
Blake!
不要啊
No!
布雷克
Blake!
布雷克 布雷克
Blake! Blake!
让开 奥利 让开
Move, Ollie. Move-move.
加油 呼吸 布雷克
Come on. Breathe, Blake.
呼吸 亲爱的
Breathe, honey.
我们得离开这儿 去砸开一扇窗户
We gotta get outta here. Break a window!
噢 天啦
Oh, my God.
让开 走远点儿
Move! Get outta the way!
小心
Watch out!
上来 快上来 快
Get on! Let's go! Let's go!
快走 快走 奥利 快上去
Move. Move, Ollie, move.
- 快来 雷 - 接住她 艾玛
- Come on, ray. - Take her, Emma.
我接住了 好了
I got her. It's okay.
好了
Here you go.
醒醒 亲爱的 醒醒啊
Wake up, honey. Come on.
让我来 我们得离开这儿 艾玛
Get her. Get us outta here, Em!
这栋楼要塌了
Okay. The building's coming down.
都趴下
Everybody down!
好了 布雷克
Okay, Blake.
爸爸和我 我们都在这儿
Okay, dad and I, we're right here now.
我们都在这儿
We're right here.
呼吸呀 布雷克 呼吸呀
Breathe, Blake. Breathe.
加油
Come on.
不要离开我 呼吸 加油
Don't leave me. Breathe. Come on.
爸爸和我都在这儿 好嘛
Dad and I are right here, all right?
雷
Ray...
我的孩子呀
My baby.
我不能再失去你了
I'm not gonna lose you, too.
绝不
No.
加油
Come on.
噢 噢 我的上帝啊
Oh. Oh, my God.
好啦 好啦
Okay. Okay.
妈妈
Mom.
我在这儿 我就在这儿
I'm right here. I'm right here.
嗯
Yeah.
没事儿了 没事儿了 没事儿了
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
现在我们可以更加清晰地看到
We are now getting a better picture
地震造成的毁坏场景
of the scale of the devastation.
而在很多街区我们都可以看到
And this was the sight in many neighborhoods:
亲朋好友相拥在一起
Families and friends huddled together,
虽然心有余悸 但依旧庆幸自己的劫后余生
shaken but grateful to still be alive.
地质学家将会密切关注
Seismologists will be keeping a close watch
全球地壳板块的活动情况
on all of the world's tectonic plates
因为圣安德烈亚斯这场地震
as the San Andreas quake
可能会波及全球
could have rippling effects throughout the globe.
让我们再来关注一下国内的情况
Closer to home, nerves are finally calming
对于只是略有震感的东海岸
on the east coast where the shaking was felt hey.
紧张的情绪终于得到平复
Across the entire eastern seaboard.
- 你做得非常好 - 政府的官员正在考虑建立一套...
- You did good. - Officials in Washington want to establish a new...
谢谢
Thank you.
这是大家的功劳
We all did.
白宫
And the white house.
以及旧金山政府
Authorities in San Francisco are attributing
对那位专家致以衷心的感谢
a tremendous amount of lives saved thanks to local experts,
正是因为他及时向大众发出地震预警从而拯救了无数人的生命
who were able to give ample warning of the massive quake.
同时 湾区的灾后重建工作也已经开始
Meanwhile, recovery efforts have begun in the bay area
联邦紧急事务管理局 国民卫队和联合国救援组织
where Fema, the national guard and U.N. Relief teams
都已经赶赴灾区
have all been mobilized.
成千上万的志愿者
Aided by the thousands of volunteers
也都纷纷奔赴湾区
pouring into the state.
我们在天上的父 愿人人都尊您的名
Our father who art in heaven, hallowed by thy name.
愿您的天国降临
Thy kingdom come...
奥利  本
Ollie. Ben.
我 我在船上找到了这个
I, uh, I found this on the boat.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿  你们对布雷克帮助 我深表感激
Hey, I wanna thank you guys for bein' there for Blake.
是啊 多谢你们
Yeah, thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
但实际上 她帮我们的更多
But it was more like she was there for us.
至少我这么觉得
I think.
这真是让人难以置信
This is incredible.
那 接下来呢
So... what now?
接下来我们重建家园
Now we rebuild.
\h\h导演
布拉德・佩顿
\h\h编剧
卡尔顿・库思
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h编剧
杰里米・帕斯摩尔&安德烈・法布里齐奥
\h\h制作人
\h\h\h比尤・弗林
\h\h执行制作人
\h\h\h\h理查德・布莱纳
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h塞缪尔・杰・布朗
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h迈克尔・迪斯科
\h\h执行制作人
\h\h\h\h托比・埃默里赫
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h史蒂文・慕钦
\h\h执行制作人
\h\h\h\h罗伯・考恩
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h特里普・文森
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h布鲁斯・伯曼
\h\h摄影指导
史蒂夫・耶迪林
\h\h美术指导
\h巴里・朱塞德
\h\h电影剪辑
\h鲍勃・杜克赛
\h\h联合制片人
海勒姆・贾西亚
\h\h道恩・强森
\h\h卡拉・古奇诺
\h\h亚历珊德拉・达达里奥
\h\h艾恩・格拉法德
\h\h阿琪・潘雅碧
\h\h保罗・吉亚玛提
\h\h雨果・约翰斯通-伯特
\h\h阿特・帕金森
\h\h凯莉・米洛
\h\h李威尹
\h选角导演
\h\h\h\h\h\h黛博拉・阿奎拉
\h\h\h\h\h\h特里西娅・伍德
\h服装设计
温迪・查克
\h\h原创音乐
安德鲁・罗金顿
\h\h视觉特效
科林・施特劳斯
\h\h来自 布拉德?佩顿 指导的电影
?树叶转黄?
All the leaves are brown
∮天空灰蓝?
And the sky is gray
?我随处闲逛?
I've been for a walk
?在这样一个冬日?
On a winter's day
?我感到安全又温暖?
I'd be safe and warm
?如果这是在洛杉矶?
If I was in L.A.
?加州之梦 噢 在这样一个冬日?
California dreamin', Oh, on such a winter's day
?树叶转黄?
All the leaves are brown
?天空灰蓝?
And the sky is gray
?我随处闲逛?
I've been for a walk
?在这样一个冬日?
On a winter's day
?我感到安全又温暖?
I'd be safe and warm
?如果这是在洛杉矶?
If I was in L.A.
?加州之梦 噢 在这样一个冬日?
California dreamin' on such a winter's day
?停车不入教堂?
I stopped into a church
?穿过走廊?
I passed along the way
?我双膝跪下?
Well, I got down on my knees
?假装祷告?
And I pretended to pray
?牧师喜欢寒冷?
You know the preacher likes the cold
?他知晓我会驻留?
He knows I'm gonna stay
?加州之梦 噢 在这样一个冬日?
California dreamin', Oh, on such a winter's day
?我感到安全又温暖?
I'd be safe and warm
?树叶转黄?
All the leaves are brown
?天空灰蓝?
And the sky is gray
?我随处闲逛?
I've been for a walk
?在这样一个冬日?
On a winter's day
?如果不是告诉了她?
If I didn't tell her
?我今天就会离去?
I could leave today
?加州之梦?
California dreamin'
?在这样一个冬日?
On such a winter's day
?噢 在这样一个冬日?
Oh, on such a winter's day
?在这样一个冬日?
On such a winter's day
?耶 耶?
Yeah, yeah